Jonathan Sharp

2006 Holloway Ct Goodlettsville, TN 37072 (615) 672-4383 (h) (615) 579-5868 (c) jon@jonsharp.net www.jonsharp.net

Objective

I am an experienced information technology professional with a diverse background, providing a unique advantage in many IT consulting roles. I seek out challenging projects that leverage my existing experience while providing new opportunities to grow. I particularly seek out opportunities to integrate open source software into real-world solutions.

Education

University of Phoenix		2004 – 2005	3.7 Cum. GPA
*	M.S. in Computer Information Systems		
Sou	uthern Adventist University	2000 – 2002	3.4 Cum. GPA
	B.S. in Computer Systems Administration		
	Minor in Computer Science		
*	Dean's list		
*	Awarded the Outstanding Senior Award by	nior Award by the School of Computing	
	Iton State College Dean's list	1998 – 2000	3.6 Cum. GPA
	orgia-Cumberland Academy National Honor Society member	1994 – 1998	3.9 Cum. GPA

Professional Experience

Network Engineer,

February 2005 – January 2006

Xebec IT

- Linux/open source consulting,
- ❖ Mac OS X Server and Macintosh integration consulting,
- ❖ Network routing, firewall, security consulting
- ❖ Planned and executed complex network infrastructure/data migration
- Web development

Information Systems Manager,

June 2003 – February 2005

NDS Media Solutions

Fulfilled all IT-related responsibilities, including:

- System administration (implementation and maintenance) of Linux and FreeBSD servers
- Developing, implementing and monitoring information systems policies and controls
- Network engineering tasks related to routing, bandwidth / traffic monitoring, log analysis, intrusion detection, etc.
- Determining cost-effective, proactive strategies for Information Technology by evaluating and recommending software and hardware purchases and/or implementation
- * Telecommunications, specifically the administration of the company's Nortel Meridian 1 PBX system
- Software development for in-house applications
- Implementing e-commerce websites, establishing merchant card processing, providing web hosting services
- ❖ Maintaining and developing the company website
- ❖ Implementing and maintaining data backup strategies and disaster recovery plans
- Providing support to end users regarding commercial software, in-house software, hardware, printing, and telecommunications equipment

Achievements include:

Developed a fulfillment/distribution application using popular LAMP platform (Linux, Apache, MySQL and PHP)

Jonathan Sharp

2006 Holloway Ct Goodlettsville, TN 37072 (615) 672-4383 (h) (615) 579-5868 (c) jon@jonsharp.net www.jonsharp.net

- ❖ Achieved 650+ day uptime with FreeBSD 4.8 server (brought down by excessive power failure)
- Developed new, automated methods for work flow, resulting in increased efficiency
- Cut telecommunications costs in half by switching to new provider for both voice and data services

Information Systems,

Sep 2000 - May 2003

Southern Adventist University

- Began in workstation support, promoted quickly to networking and then employed as embedded systems developer
- ❖ Developed a digital time clock / debit system for the university campus
- ❖ Installed and maintained many critical servers in a highly heterogeneous environment (Windows 2000, Linux, Solaris)
- ❖ Installed and maintained critical networking components including switches, routers, and various datacenter equipment in our NOC
- Authored various network management scripts using Perl, PHP, MySQL
- Contributed to the design and implementation of network security strategies

Precision Computer Service

Apr 1999 - Aug 2000

- ❖ Performed Novell Netware administrative and engineering tasks
- * Responsible for Linux / Unix / Windows NT system administration
- Performed network troubleshooting
- Provided onsite support (Clients included small businesses, schools, and government offices)

Skills Matrix (items listed in descending order of experience):

Operating Systems: Windows (95/98/NT/2000/XP), Linux, FreeBSD, Mac OS (System 7 – OS X 10.4), OpenBSD,

NetBSD, Novell Netware (4.11 - 5.1), Solaris (2.6 - 9), QNX, OS/2 (Warp 4), SCO Unix,

many other experimental OSes

Programming PHP, Java, Z80 ASM, C/C++, 8051 ASM, Perl, Python, Objective C, C#/J# .NET/Mono

Languages:

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS Access, MS SQL 7/2000, Oracle, FileMaker Pro

Networking: Firewalling / VPN technologies (SonicWall, Symantec, IPsec (KAME, FreeS/WAN), BSD's

ipfw / ipfilter, Linux's IPTables, Checkpoint), Cisco IOS (light routers and Catalyst switches), DNS administration (Bind), mail server administration (Postfix, Sendmail, MS Exchange), IPv6 routing, WiFi (802.11b, g) deployment, OpenLDAP, Open Directory, NetInfo, RADIUS

Hardware Platforms: PC (x86), Apple (m68k, PPC), Sun and other miscellaneous hardware platforms

Telecommunications: Nortel Meridian 1 PBX administration, Asterisk, Hylafax fax server software, VoIP, SIP, AIX **Misc. Software:** Vi/Vim, MS Office (97/2000/XP), MS Visio, MS Visual Studio .NET, Crystal Reports (8.5),

MAS 200 for SQL, Act! 6, Tapeware 7.0, Veritas Backup Exec, Nagios

Web Technologies: HTML, PHP / MySQL / Apache related development, XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML,

XSL/XSLT, Java Servlets

Embedded Systems: Embedded systems design

Electronic component soldering / assembly including surface mount (SMD) technology, Intimate experience with Dallas Semiconductor's TINI reference platform (hw & sw

development),

Other Skills: Amateur video game console development,

Good writing and communication skills.

Knowledge in biblical Greek

References available upon request